Dominic Crofoot | Software Developer

Profiles

Driven Software Developer with 1+ years of experience. Skilled in web development and hybrid mobile development. With backgrounds in Java, Javascript, Struts 2, Hibernate, GraphQL, React, React Native and Redux. Graduated in the Spring of 2019 with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from the University of Maryland Baltimore County.

Annapolis, MD 21401 (240) 691-9285 crofoot.github.io dominic.crofoot@gmail.com

Experience

Full Stack Developer @ Anne Arundel County, Office of Information Technology September 2019 - Present // Annapolis, MD

- Implemented inventory web application with JWT Authentication and a GraphQL based backend. As well as a React based frontend that supplied visual real time data of each department's completion of inventory.
- Developed private npm packages for internal use. Packages include generic reusable GraphQL server with builtin Google, and Active Directory authentication, and reusable Grid built for GraphQL queries.
- Web application for Anne Arundel County Police Department for processing incoming detainees charges and information. Application could produce a filled out pdf based off detainees information used for legal purposes.

Full Stack Developer Intern @ Anne Arundel County, Office of Information Technology September 2016 - September 2019 // Annapolis, MD

- Developed backend APIs with Java, and Javascript related stacks, and frontend UIs with React, JQuery, and Bootstrap.
- Designed architecture and developed mobile inventory application for scanning and tracking inventory for all departments within the county. Built with Expo, React Native and Redux.
- GraphQL proxy application that supplies a GraphQL layer to legacy rest systems.
- Introduced and developed Javascript stack for other developers to use.
- Agile Scrum based development with the use of Jira.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science @ University of Maryland, Baltimore County

August 2017 - May 2019 // Baltimore, MD

Information Assurance & Cyber Security @ Anne Arundel Community College August 2015 - July 2017 // Arnold, MD

- Cyber Security Club Secretary September 2015 July 2017
- Computer Science Club Co-Founder, Vice President April 2016 July 2017

Skills

Programming Languages

Java, Javascript (ES6), Typescript, HTML, CSS, Python

Libraries & Frameworks

React Native, GraphQL, React, Redux, Expo, TypeORM, Apollo, jQuery, Struts 2, Hibernate, Express, Type-GraphQL, Maven, Bootstrap

Server Technology

MongoDB, SQL Server, Virtualbox, Tomcat, Docker, AWS

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Bitbucket, Jira, Google Dev Console, Toad, Postman, TravisCl

Projects

react-apollo-notifications

React notification component that takes a GraphQL subscription query

Personal Expense Tracker

Built with Typescript, React, Postgres and Express

Interests

Cooking, Hockey, Swimming, Hiking, Traveling